Hello and welcome to this course on React Query, which is a library for server state management for
REACT.
I'm so glad you've decided to take this course.
I want to start out by talking about how I discovered react query, I was coding my Web site and I wanted
to be able to add coupons to courses.
So I have courses on my Web site and I wanted to be able to add coupons.
And the way the site is structured, coupons aren't loaded separately.
You load courses and the coupons come with them.
So I wanted to update the courses, the on the website, I wanted to update the course information from
the server after I added a coupon.
My first attempt was to manage this with Redox and let me tell you, it was not simple.
I had to maintain state and use actions to make sure that I refer to the courses whenever I did an update
for the coupons.
Then I remembered hearing something about react query, and I wondered whether this might help in my
situation, so I decided to give it a try and it was just easy.
I updated a coupon.
Then after the coupon update was successful, I invalidated the course data from the server and then
react query.
Did it automatically fetch?
This tool was billed for exactly this type of problem.
More specifically, react query, it maintains server state on the client.
So when you fetch your server data, you do it through react query.
Your job is to react, Quirino, when it needs to refresh the data in the cash.
You can do it immediately by invalidating data like I did with my courses when I updated a coupon,
I invalidated the courses to let React Quirino it needed to refresh that data.
Or you can mark data as stale, you can tell react query when data is stale, and then there are triggers
to refresh data when it's stale, for example, when the window is refocussed.
So that's the basic function of react query is to maintain server state on the client, but you also
get loading and error status while the data is being fetched, you get pagination an infinite scroll.
There are tools for that with react query that will look at in this course prefixing.
I have a little crystal ball here because if you anticipate what data your customer might need, your
user might need, then you can pre fetch it.
So it's there and the user doesn't have to wait for it.
Mutation's, here's my poor mutant human with green skin, you can mutate data on the server through
react query.
Deduplication of requests, so by maintaining this cache of data on the server, you can have different
components, be asking for the same data and not have to worry that you're pinging the server over and
over needlessly.
There's retry on error.
And then there are callbacks, you can run callbacks on a successful fetch of data from the server,
you can run a callback on an error, you can run callbacks on settled meaning whether when when the
whole thing is done, whether it was an error or successful and so forth.
And so this all combines into a very valuable, very smart tool to be able to do what you need to do
with server state on your client.
All right, join me in the next lecture where I will introduce how this course is structured.